<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Joseph Dykstra&apos;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
    <updated>2018-09-20T23:41:39Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
        <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
        <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://josephdykstra.com"/>
    <subtitle>Follow Joseph&apos;s opinions on your feed reader!</subtitle>
    <logo>http://josephdykstra.com/logo.png</logo>
    <rights>Copyright © Joseph Dykstra 2016.</rights>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to set up Tiny Tiny RSS on a Digital Ocean VPS]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/how-to-setup-tt-rss-on-do-vps</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/how-to-setup-tt-rss-on-do-vps">
        </link>
        <updated>2018-05-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Setting up <a href="https://tt-rss.org/">Tiny Tiny RSS</a> can be a bit tricky, even if you have some technical knowledge. I ran into a few issues when I set it up, and found solutions which I thought might come in handy for others who try to set up Tiny Tiny RSS.</p>
<h2 id="what-you-need">What you need:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> account</li>
<li>SSH Client - I use <a href="https://putty.org/">PuTTY</a> (Windows)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="create-the-vps">Create the VPS</h2>
<p>Log into your <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> account, and create a new droplet. Choose the One-Click App called <strong>LAMP on 16.04</strong>.</p>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/01-lamp.PNG" alt="Lamp on 16.04"></p>
<p>I chose the cheapest, smallest server.</p>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/02-size.PNG" alt="cheapest server"></p>
<p>Hit <strong>Create</strong>!</p>
<h2 id="login-to-the-vps">Login to the VPS</h2>
<p>Open your SSH client, and log into your new VPS. You will need to copy the IP address from the Digital Ocean dashboard. If you did not add any SSH keys, then you will have to wait for the root password in an email. In my experience, this email can come 30 minutes after creating the server.</p>
<p>Login with the VPS's IP and the username <strong>root</strong>.</p>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/05-putty.PNG" alt="Login to VPS"></p>
<p>On your first login, you might have to accept the key fingerprint.</p>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/06-putty-confirm-fingerprint.PNG" alt="Confirm fingerprint"></p>
<h2 id="install-mysql">Install MySQL</h2>
<p>Get the MySQL password by running <code>cat .digitalocean_password</code>.</p>
<p>Copy the password. In PuTTY, selecting the text copies it to the clipboard.</p>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/07-cat-do-pw.PNG" alt="cat digitalocean_password"></p>
<p>Install MySQL by running <code>mysql_secure_installation --use-default</code>. When the password prompt pops up, paste the password. (In PuTTY, just right click to paste. You won't see the screen change.) Then press <kbd>Enter</kbd>.</p>
<h2 id="set-up-mysql">Set Up MySQL</h2>
<pre><code class="language-bash">mysql --user=root --password=[Your copied password]
mysql&gt; CREATE DATABASE ttrss;
mysql&gt; exit
</code></pre>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/08-mysql-create-db.PNG" alt="Create Database"></p>
<h2 id="install-php-plugins">Install PHP Plugins</h2>
<p>Paste the following commands into the console:</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">apt-get update
apt-get install php-mbstring -y
apt-get install php-xml -y
apt-get install php-curl -y
service apache2 restart
</code></pre>
<h2 id="install-tiny-tiny-rss">Install Tiny Tiny RSS</h2>
<pre><code class="language-bash">cd /var/www/html
git clone https://tt-rss.org/git/tt-rss.git tt-rss
chmod -R 777 tt-rss
</code></pre>
<p>Visit <strong>[IP]/tt-rss/install/</strong> in your browser, and fill in the fields:</p>
<ol>
<li>Database type is <strong>MySQL</strong>.</li>
<li>Username is <strong>root</strong>.</li>
<li>Password is the one you copied earlier.</li>
<li>Database name is whatever you put after the <code>CREATE DATABASE</code> command, in this case <strong>ttrss</strong>.</li>
<li>Leave Host name empty. (This is the host name for the database server, which defaults to <strong>localhost</strong>.)</li>
<li>Port is <strong>3306</strong>.</li>
<li>Tiny Tiny RSS URL should be left as-is.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/09-ttrss-install.PNG" alt="Install TTRSS"></p>
<p>Press <strong>Test configuration</strong>. I got a minor warning about internationalized domain names, which I ignored.</p>
<p>Press <strong>Initialize database</strong>.</p>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/14-ttrss-initialize-db2.PNG" alt="Init db"></p>
<p>Press <strong>Save configuration</strong>.</p>
<p>Visit <strong>[IP]/tt-rss/</strong> in your browser.</p>
<ol>
<li>Login is <strong>admin</strong>.</li>
<li>Password is <strong>password</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="./how-to-setup-ttrss/15-login.PNG" alt="Login"></p>
<p>Change the password when you log in!</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DCC Podcast Feeds]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/dcc-podcast-feeds</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/dcc-podcast-feeds">
        </link>
        <updated>2018-02-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com">My church</a> has an RSS feed, and I want to listen through sermon series with my <a href="./android-podcast-apps-review">podcast app</a>. There are a few problems with this:</p>
<ul>
<li>The RSS feed has thousands of entries. This makes it tough to find and download a series.</li>
<li>The RSS feed has sermons and communion meditations (mini-sermons) all mixed together.</li>
<li>The RSS feed has some unrelated sermons in the middle of a series.</li>
</ul>
<p>I was going to make a scraper that would look up the sermons in a series, and create an RSS file, but I found that my church's website will dynamically generate an RSS feed for a series. There is not a way to open a series' RSS feed using the church's website.</p>
<p>Now the problem is that it's not very easy to get a link to a series' RSS feed... Until now!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=12">Life of David</a> (130 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=36">Revelation</a> (90 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=9">Acts</a> (68 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=48">Foundations</a> (30 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=49">Christian and Prosperity</a> (22 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=10">Galatians</a> (17 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=47">Esther</a> (12 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=46">James</a> (12 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=28">Ecclesiastes</a> (11 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=4">Beatitudes</a> (9 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=17">Christian Materialism</a> (7 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=6">Evangelism</a> (7 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=56">Titus - Waging War</a> (7 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=58">Nehemiah</a> (6 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=32">Five Reformation Solas</a> (5 sermons)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dominioncovenantchurch.com/?podcast&amp;series=45">Holy Trinity</a> (5 sermons)</li>
</ul>
<p>This does not have every single series, but it does have most series with five or more sermons. Click the Edit link below to add another series.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017 Christmas Letter]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/2017-dykstra-christmas-letter</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/2017-dykstra-christmas-letter">
        </link>
        <updated>2018-02-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A big "Howdy" from the Dykstras!</p>
<p>We have been busy, but busy is good.  Gilbert is still keeping bees, and is transitioning from primarily producing honey to producing more queen bees.  Donna is keeping the house, garden, and kids in check.  Joseph is still working as a programmer for a School Information System vendor.  Levi is still working for a landscaper family-friend, and taking horticulture classes.  Daniel is still working for David, who is a General Contractor.  Nathanael is being homeschooled by Donna, and is currently in Seventh grade.</p>
<p>In mid-March Gilbert and the boys moved Rebecca's baby grand piano from our house to Micah and Rebecca's house.</p>
<p>Our family has a weekly gathering on Saturday nights where all the married children and their families come for pizza or sloppy joes. In mid-March, Michael came in with a shirt that said "Dad-To-Be". What a cute way to announce their pregnancy!</p>
<p>In late April, Gilbert, Donna, Daniel, and Nathanael attended the First LEGO League World Championship in St. Louis, Missouri.  Nathanael is on a team called the Data Dragons, created by a family in our church.  The team</p>
<p>In early May, Joseph's company flew his team to Texas for an in-person meetup. Joseph works from his "remote bunker" for the Texas-based company.</p>
<p>In June, Donna's parents moved from their house of 40ish years to a condo across town, and our family helped them move.  It's a huge change for them, and it's still a little hard to believe that they are living somewhere else.</p>
<p>August was a busy month.  Our church hosted a conference called the Providential History Festival.  Levi played the role of a guard for a drama at PHF.</p>
<p>Nathanael joined a local homeschool junior-varsity flag-football team called Lightning.  The team won three of five official games.</p>
<p>In late-August, our family drove to North-East Nebraska to view the solar eclipse.  Unfortunately clouds covered the sun during totality where we were, but we still got to see a lot of the eclipse clearly.</p>
<p>In September, we had a family "Staycation".  All of the married children and their families came over to our house for a week.  One day we visited the zoo.  One night was "guy's night" where the guys played laser tag.  The girls went to an escape room for "girl's night".  During the staycation we played tons of board games, and even had some tournaments for ping pong, rook, and giant jenga. (Giant jenga is jenga, but with 2x4s).</p>
<p>On October 22, Michael and Elizabeth's first child was born.  She was named Abigail Delores Dykstra.  She is Gilbert and Donna's eighth grandchild.</p>
<p>In December, Micah and Rebecca had a baby shower for their (unborn) boy.</p>
<p>2017 has been another great year for the Dykstras, and we sincerely hope that you've had a great year too!  Remember that this season is about Christ's incarnation, and our joy in salvation through Him.  We thank you all for being our friends throughout this year!</p>
<p>— The Dykstra Family</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Highlight CFML Tags in Sublime Text 3]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/highlight-cfml-in-sublime</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/highlight-cfml-in-sublime">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-06-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use Sublime Text 3, and in my day job, I write and edit code in ColdFusion Markup Language (CFML), so I wanted a syntax highlighter. You can use Sublime's built-in HTML highlighter, but then you can't easily distinguish CFML tags from plain HTML tags:</p>
<p><img src="./highlight-cfml-in-sublime/1_initial.png" alt="Initial"></p>
<p>Let me show you a more excellent way.</p>
<p>If you don't already have <a href="https://packagecontrol.io">Package Control</a>, then go to <em>Tools</em> &gt; <em>Install Package Control</em>.</p>
<p>If you don't already have the CFML package, then press <kbd>Ctrl/Cmd</kbd><kbd>Shift</kbd><kbd>P</kbd>. Then type <strong>Install Package</strong>, and press <kbd>Enter</kbd>. Then type <strong>CFML</strong>, and press <kbd>Enter</kbd>.</p>
<p>If you want CFML tags to be visually distinct from HTML tags then go to <em>Preferences</em> &gt; <em>Package Settings</em> &gt; <em>CFML</em> &gt; <em>Settings</em>, and paste the following code:</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">{
    // color scheme styles to inject for Lucee/CFML tags
    // valid keys are "foreground" and "fontStyle"
    // "foreground": "#RRGGBB", "#RGB" or ""
    // "fontStyle": "bold", "italic", "bold italic", or ""
    "cfml_tag_style": { "foreground": "#4C9BB0", "fontStyle": "" },
    "cfml_tag_attribute_style": { "foreground": "", "fontStyle": "" }
}
</code></pre>
<p>Save the file.</p>
<p>The example code above will modify the tag style but not the attribute style. Customize it it to your liking.</p>
<p>To actually enable it, you must press <kbd>Ctrl/Cmd</kbd><kbd>Shift</kbd><kbd>P</kbd>. Then type <strong>CFML Toggle</strong>, and press <kbd>Enter</kbd>.</p>
<p><img src="./highlight-cfml-in-sublime/3_cfml_package_toggle.png" alt="CFML Package Color Toggle"></p>
<p>If you hate the CF tag color that you just chose, then go ahead and change the foreground color. You will have to run the <strong>CFML Toggle</strong> two times to see the new color.</p>
<p>Now your CFML files look like this:</p>
<p><img src="./highlight-cfml-in-sublime/4_highlighted.png" alt="Success"></p>
<p>I had the custom color go away, and running the <strong>CFML Toggle</strong> a couple times didn't make it show. I changed the theme, then changed it back, then I ran the toggle a couple more times, and it started working again.</p>
<p>I hope this helps!</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complaints about Memes]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/complaints-about-memes</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/complaints-about-memes">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I saw a lot of memes on Facebook, and I was disappointed in humanity. First, for the memes, and second, for the content. So I grabbed a bunch of memes from my timeline. (Not all the memes, some of them were just dumb jokes. Also, I'm using the term "meme" quite loosely.)</p>
<p>First, the pencil joke:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/1_pencil_cassette.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>I wouldn't even include this one if it wasn't for the text at the top: "Like three people will get this but it's worth it."</p>
<p>Here's a comic strip that's well done, but not particularly sharable... Until you add the text telling almost everyone that they are the genius that understands this joke. At least 50% of people must get the joke, is my estimate, but the text at the top is intended to make you feel good. And then you Like or Share it, and more people see it in their timeline.</p>
<hr>
<p>I guess you can tell that I'm growing up in the Mid-West with farming relatives:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/2_baling_hard_work.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>This meme is similar the the first, but targets what they've done instead of what they know. While fewer people relate to this, those who do are probably going to Share and Like it more often.</p>
<p>If you've spent a summer baling hay, you want your friends to know. What better way to tell them, then to also tell them that they haven't worked hard?</p>
<hr>
<p>The inspirational, misleading meme:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/3_do_scary_things.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>"Do things that scare you, they're worth it."</p>
<p>Jumping off a cliff would scare me.</p>
<hr>
<p>Thoughts and prayers:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/4_thoughts_prayers.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>I found this to be pretty funny. In a case where the guy on the dock is in a position to help, it's pretty terrible that he's ignoring the drowning dude.</p>
<p>In cases where I've noticed people say this, I don't think they were in the position to help...</p>
<hr>
<p>Here's a girl who wrote a song about her situation, and sang it for America's Got Talent, even though she's deaf:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/5_mandy_harvey.png" alt="Image"></p>
<p>I watched it, and was impressed. Then again, I've been impressed with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rk_qLtk0m2c">many</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/NS0L9RdPNvY?t=2m49s">Got</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/CVRe8lns3xc?t=39s">Talent</a> videos, each in different ways.</p>
<p>The caption is dumb. "Proof that you should never give up on your dream"? <em>Maybe</em> it's evidence that you should never give up on your dream. It's proof that some people <em>accomplish</em> their dreams. Maybe your dream is out of reach. Maybe you should get a more realistic dream.</p>
<hr>
<p>Now for some of the dumbest logic yet:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/6_wine_college.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>This makes just enough sense to click Like if you aren't really thinking about it, and never set eyes upon it again.</p>
<p>The meme is trying to say this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Can I spend $20?" "No."</p>
<p>"Can I spend $40,000?" "Yes."</p>
<p>Subtext: Isn't that crazy?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Obviously it can be bad, even disastrous to go into debt. It's legal to go into debt. Colleges are a common method by which people go into debt. Should colleges be illegal? No! People can decide for themselves whether college is worth the investment.</p>
<p>The first part of the meme has nothing to do with the second part, which I just covered. It just mentions that alcohol is illegal in the U.S. I don't think it should be, but that's not really the point of the meme.</p>
<hr>
<p>I thought this was another one of those "I had no smartphone when I was a kid" memes:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/7_grew_up_no_phone.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>Ha ha, nope! I think this meme is hilarious. But like most of the other memes, it suffers from terrible resolution and jpg compression.</p>
<p>It only makes sense with the context of the "so glad I grew up playing outdoors rather than playing with a screen" memes.</p>
<hr>
<p>So what's the point? I felt like complaining about what I see on Facebook. While I would like to blame the "algorithm" that tries to guess what I want to see, it's actually a lot of my friends interacting (Sharing/Liking) these posts that gets me to see them. And I've probably Liked and Shared a hundred dumb memes, so I'm not one to talk.</p>
<p>But if you see a meme on Facebook or Twitter, think about this: Is it a logical argument? Is it just appealing to pride?</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>