<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Joseph Dykstra&apos;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
    <updated>2018-02-09T23:42:29Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
        <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
        <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://josephdykstra.com"/>
    <subtitle>Follow Joseph&apos;s opinions on your feed reader!</subtitle>
    <logo>http://josephdykstra.com/logo.png</logo>
    <rights>Copyright © Joseph Dykstra 2016.</rights>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Highlight CFML Tags in Sublime Text 3]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/highlight-cfml-in-sublime</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/highlight-cfml-in-sublime">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-06-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use Sublime Text 3, and in my day job, I write and edit code in ColdFusion Markup Language (CFML), so I wanted a syntax highlighter. You can use Sublime's built-in HTML highlighter, but then you can't easily distinguish CFML tags from plain HTML tags:</p>
<p><img src="./highlight-cfml-in-sublime/1_initial.png" alt="Initial"></p>
<p>Let me show you a more excellent way.</p>
<p>If you don't already have <a href="https://packagecontrol.io">Package Control</a>, then go to <em>Tools</em> &gt; <em>Install Package Control</em>.</p>
<p>If you don't already have the CFML package, then press <kbd>Ctrl/Cmd</kbd><kbd>Shift</kbd><kbd>P</kbd>. Then type <strong>Install Package</strong>, and press <kbd>Enter</kbd>. Then type <strong>CFML</strong>, and press <kbd>Enter</kbd>.</p>
<p>If you want CFML tags to be visually distinct from HTML tags then go to <em>Preferences</em> &gt; <em>Package Settings</em> &gt; <em>CFML</em> &gt; <em>Settings</em>, and paste the following code:</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">{
    // color scheme styles to inject for Lucee/CFML tags
    // valid keys are "foreground" and "fontStyle"
    // "foreground": "#RRGGBB", "#RGB" or ""
    // "fontStyle": "bold", "italic", "bold italic", or ""
    "cfml_tag_style": { "foreground": "#4C9BB0", "fontStyle": "" },
    "cfml_tag_attribute_style": { "foreground": "", "fontStyle": "" }
}
</code></pre>
<p>Save the file.</p>
<p>The example code above will modify the tag style but not the attribute style. Customize it it to your liking.</p>
<p>To actually enable it, you must press <kbd>Ctrl/Cmd</kbd><kbd>Shift</kbd><kbd>P</kbd>. Then type <strong>CFML Toggle</strong>, and press <kbd>Enter</kbd>.</p>
<p><img src="./highlight-cfml-in-sublime/3_cfml_package_toggle.png" alt="CFML Package Color Toggle"></p>
<p>If you hate the CF tag color that you just chose, then go ahead and change the foreground color. You will have to run the <strong>CFML Toggle</strong> two times to see the new color.</p>
<p>Now your CFML files look like this:</p>
<p><img src="./highlight-cfml-in-sublime/4_highlighted.png" alt="Success"></p>
<p>I hope this helps!</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complaints about Memes]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/complaints-about-memes</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/complaints-about-memes">
        </link>
        <updated>2017-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I saw a lot of memes on Facebook, and I was disappointed in humanity. First, for the memes, and second, for the content. So I grabbed a bunch of memes from my timeline. (Not all the memes, some of them were just dumb jokes. Also, I'm using the term "meme" quite loosely.)</p>
<p>First, the pencil joke:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/1_pencil_cassette.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>I wouldn't even include this one if it wasn't for the text at the top: "Like three people will get this but it's worth it."</p>
<p>Here's a comic strip that's well done, but not particularly sharable... Until you add the text telling almost everyone that they are the genius that understands this joke. At least 50% of people must get the joke, is my estimate, but the text at the top is intended to make you feel good. And then you Like or Share it, and more people see it in their timeline.</p>
<hr>
<p>I guess you can tell that I'm growing up in the Mid-West with farming relatives:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/2_baling_hard_work.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>This meme is similar the the first, but targets what they've done instead of what they know. While fewer people relate to this, those who do are probably going to Share and Like it more often.</p>
<p>If you've spent a summer baling hay, you want your friends to know. What better way to tell them, then to also tell them that they haven't worked hard?</p>
<hr>
<p>The inspirational, misleading meme:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/3_do_scary_things.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>"Do things that scare you, they're worth it."</p>
<p>Jumping off a cliff would scare me.</p>
<hr>
<p>Thoughts and prayers:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/4_thoughts_prayers.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>I found this to be pretty funny. In a case where the guy on the dock is in a position to help, it's pretty terrible that he's ignoring the drowning dude.</p>
<p>In cases where I've noticed people say this, I don't think they were in the position to help...</p>
<hr>
<p>Here's a girl who wrote a song about her situation, and sang it for America's Got Talent, even though she's deaf:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/5_mandy_harvey.png" alt="Image"></p>
<p>I watched it, and was impressed. Then again, I've been impressed with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rk_qLtk0m2c">many</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/NS0L9RdPNvY?t=2m49s">Got</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/CVRe8lns3xc?t=39s">Talent</a> videos, each in different ways.</p>
<p>The caption is dumb. "Proof that you should never give up on your dream"? <em>Maybe</em> it's evidence that you should never give up on your dream. It's proof that some people <em>accomplish</em> their dreams. Maybe your dream is out of reach. Maybe you should get a more realistic dream.</p>
<hr>
<p>Now for some of the dumbest logic yet:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/6_wine_college.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>This makes just enough sense to click Like if you aren't really thinking about it, and never set eyes upon it again.</p>
<p>The meme is trying to say this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Can I spend $20?" "No."</p>
<p>"Can I spend $40,000?" "Yes."</p>
<p>Subtext: Isn't that crazy?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Obviously it can be bad, even disastrous to go into debt. It's legal to go into debt. Colleges are a common method by which people go into debt. Should colleges be illegal? No! People can decide for themselves whether college is worth the investment.</p>
<p>The first part of the meme has nothing to do with the second part, which I just covered. It just mentions that alcohol is illegal in the U.S. I don't think it should be, but that's not really the point of the meme.</p>
<hr>
<p>I thought this was another one of those "I had no smartphone when I was a kid" memes:</p>
<p><img src="./complaints-about-memes/7_grew_up_no_phone.jpg" alt="Image"></p>
<p>Ha ha, nope! I think this meme is hilarious. But like most of the other memes, it suffers from terrible resolution and jpg compression.</p>
<p>It only makes sense with the context of the "so glad I grew up playing outdoors rather than playing with a screen" memes.</p>
<hr>
<p>So what's the point? I felt like complaining about what I see on Facebook. While I would like to blame the "algorithm" that tries to guess what I want to see, it's actually a lot of my friends interacting (Sharing/Liking) these posts that gets me to see them. And I've probably Liked and Shared a hundred dumb memes, so I'm not one to talk.</p>
<p>But if you see a meme on Facebook or Twitter, think about this: Is it a logical argument? Is it just appealing to pride?</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016 Christmas Letter]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/2016-dykstra-christmas-letter</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/2016-dykstra-christmas-letter">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-12-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello from the Dykstra Family!</p>
<p>What a crazy year 2016 has been for us!  Gilbert has been beekeeping, and he added onto his shed (with the boys' help).  Gilbert and Donna planted, watered, tended, and harvested our garden.  Donna and Rebecca went to a camp called Joni and Friends where they assisted families of disabled children.  Rebecca got married!  (Some said it would never happen, but I guess she proved them wrong!)  Joseph is working as a computer programmer.  Levi is working for a landscaper, and is in college for horticulture.  Daniel is working for David who is a general contractor, and is in college to become an electrician.  Nathanael is still being homeschooled.</p>
<p>In January, Jordon and Jessica had their 4th child, Isabella Cave.</p>
<p>In February, Micah Swab's courtship with Rebecca was announced.  (For the uninitiated, courting is like dating, but with Gilbert and Donna being more involved, which they quite liked!)  Micah asked for Gilbert and Donna's permission to court Rebecca several months prior.  A few of the kids had suspicions that Micah was starting a courtship.  We were all elated to have his suitorship confirmed.</p>
<p>March marked Gilbert and Donna's 31st Anniversary.  They left the kids at the house (scary!) and went to a Bed &amp; Breakfast near Plattsmouth, Nebraska.</p>
<p>May was a busy month!  Levi graduated from High School, so we hosted a graduation party which featured volleyball and delicious beverages.  Unfortunately Levi may have had a little too much of both, because about a week later, he was admitted to the hospital and had his appendix removed.
Gilbert and Donna drove Daniel and Nathanael to the Lego Razorback competition in Arkansas where they competed  with their FLL team.
Jordon and Jessica moved to Glenwood, Iowa after Jordon accepted a job in Clarinda, Iowa.  Seth and Laura moved from their apartment into a house, also in May.</p>
<p>Early in July, Micah proposed to Rebecca.  She said yes, of course, and so we ate ice cream and watched the hidden-camera footage of the proposal.  It was adorable!
Later in July, we had a family from church camp in our back-yard.  They had to move due to their husband's military job, and providentially their house sold more quickly than they expected.  They were awesome guests, and we thoroughly enjoyed our time together!  A fringe benefit for us was, they took care of the house and dog chores while we went on vacation.
In mid-July, we left on vacation to Alberta, Canada.  We wanted one last family vacation before Rebecca left.  We saw all kinds of wildlife and majestic landscapes.</p>
<p>In August, David and Ruth had their 3rd child, Jochebed Dykstra.</p>
<p>Late in October, our brave back-yard campers left for the outpost where they were stationed.  It was sad to see them go.</p>
<p>Micah and Rebecca's wedding was in December.  They were married in the oldest church in Nebraska.  They will return from their honeymoon a few days after Christmas.</p>
<p>We hope you all had an awesome year too!</p>
<p>Love,
The Dykstra Family</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Misinterpreting Matthew 24]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/misinterpreting-matthew-24</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/misinterpreting-matthew-24">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-09-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Matthew 24:1-34</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Then Jesus went out and departed from the temple, and His disciples came up to show Him the buildings of the temple. And Jesus said to them, "Do you not see all these things? Assuredly, I say to you, not one stone shall be left here upon another, that shall not be thrown down."</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now as He sat on the Mount of Olives, the disciples came to Him privately, saying, "Tell us, when will these things be? And what will be the sign of Your coming, and of the end of the age?"</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And Jesus answered and said to them: "Take heed that no one deceives you. For many will come in My name, saying, 'I am the Christ,' and will deceive many. And you will hear of wars and rumors of wars. See that you are not troubled; for all these things must come to pass, but the end is not yet. For nation will rise against nation, and kingdom against kingdom. And there will be famines, pestilences, and earthquakes in various places. All these are the beginning of sorrows.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Then they will deliver you up to tribulation and kill you, and you will be hated by all nations for My name's sake. And then many will be offended, will betray one another, and will hate one another. Then many false prophets will rise up and deceive many. And because lawlessness will abound, the love of many will grow cold. But he who endures to the end shall be saved. And this gospel of the kingdom will be preached in all the world as a witness to all the nations, and then the end will come.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Therefore when you see the 'abomination of desolation,' spoken of by Daniel the prophet, standing in the holy place" (whoever reads, let him understand), "then let those who are in Judea flee to the mountains. Let him who is on the housetop not go down to take anything out of his house. And let him who is in the field not go back to get his clothes. But woe to those who are pregnant and to those who are nursing babies in those days! And pray that your flight may not be in winter or on the Sabbath. For then there will be great tribulation, such as has not been since the beginning of the world until this time, no, nor ever shall be. And unless those days were shortened, no flesh would be saved; but for the elect's sake those days will be shortened.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Then if anyone says to you, 'Look, here is the Christ!' or 'There!' do not believe it. For false christs and false prophets will rise and show great signs and wonders to deceive, if possible, even the elect. See, I have told you beforehand.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Therefore if they say to you, 'Look, He is in the desert!' do not go out; or 'Look, He is in the inner rooms!' do not believe it. For as the lightning comes from the east and flashes to the west, so also will the coming of the Son of Man be. For wherever the carcass is, there the eagles will be gathered together.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Immediately after the tribulation of those days the sun will be darkened, and the moon will not give its light; the stars will fall from heaven, and the powers of the heavens will be shaken. Then the sign of the Son of Man will appear in heaven, and then all the tribes of the earth will mourn, and they will see the Son of Man coming on the clouds of heaven with power and great glory. And He will send His angels with a great sound of a trumpet, and they will gather together His elect from the four winds, from one end of heaven to the other.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now learn this parable from the fig tree: When its branch has already become tender and puts forth leaves, you know that summer is near. So you also, when you see all these things, know that it is near—at the doors! Assuredly, I say to you, this generation will by no means pass away till all these things take place. Heaven and earth will pass away, but My words will by no means pass away.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you are unaware of how many Christians see this passage, try reading this: <a href="http://heavenscity.com/2016/04/05/5-signs-that-jesus-is-going-to-return-soon/">5 signs that Jesus is going to return soon</a>, and maybe the comment section as well (if you're into that sort of thing).</p>
<p>The Great Tribulation has already happened. You can read about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siege_of_Jerusalem_(AD_70)">Siege of Jerusalem</a>. If you hear wars an rumors of wars today, it doesn't mean Jesus is coming back soon, since this prophecy has already been fulfilled.</p>
<p>Jesus says very plainly that the Tribulation will occur in some of the listeners' lifetimes.</p>
<p>After talking about the Siege of Jerusalem, Jesus went on to talk about the end times. (Remember that His disciples asked about both the destruction of the temple, and the end times in verse 3.)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But of that day and hour no one knows, not even the angels of heaven, but My Father only. But as the days of Noah were, so also will the coming of the Son of Man be. For as in the days before the flood, they were eating and drinking, marrying and giving in marriage, until the day that Noah entered the ark, and did not know until the flood came and took them all away, so also will the coming of the Son of Man be. Then two men will be in the field: one will be taken and the other left. Two women will be grinding at the mill: one will be taken and the other left. Watch therefore, for you do not know what hour your Lord is coming. But know this, that if the master of the house had known what hour the thief would come, he would have watched and not allowed his house to be broken into. Therefore you also be ready, for the Son of Man is coming at an hour you do not expect."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Here, Jesus explains that we <em>won't</em> have signs telling us when the end times are coming. If the Great Tribulation = End Times, then this makes no sense, becuase Jesus Himself just told them signs for the Great Tribulation!</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Vote For a Candidate That Can't Win]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/a-vote-for-a-candidate-that-cant-win</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/a-vote-for-a-candidate-that-cant-win">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-08-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you heard this?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A vote for a candidate that has no chance of winning is a vote for the majority.</p>
<p>— Facebook Comment</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am not convinced that a vote for a candidate that can't win is a vote for the leader (a.k.a. "majority"). I've decided to run the numbers.</p>
<hr>
<p>Let's imagine that there are 10,000 voters, not including you:</p>
<ul>
<li>4500 are voting for Candidate Clam Chowder</li>
<li>4000 are voting for Kandidate Ketchup</li>
<li>1500 are voting for Candidate Creamy Cool Whip</li>
</ul>
<p>You are a supporter of Candidate Creamy Cool Whip, and you strongly <em>distaste</em> Candidate Clam Chowder. You're not a fan of Kandidate Ketchup, but <em>"Ketchup is a bit better than Clam Chowder"</em>, you tell yourself.</p>
<p>Election day is coming up, and the Ketchuppers say that if you don't vote for Kandidate Ketchup, you're voting for Candidate Clam Chowder.</p>
<p>Here are the two scenarios:</p>
<ol>
<li>You give in to the demands, and cast your vote for Ketchup</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Clam Chowder: 4500 votes</li>
<li>Ketchup: 4001 votes</li>
<li>Creamy Cool Whip: 1500 votes</li>
</ul>
<ol start="2">
<li>You say "deal with it!" to the Ketchuppers, and you stand with your fellow Cool Whippers</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Clam Chowder: 4500 votes</li>
<li>Ketchup: 4000 votes</li>
<li>Creamy Cool Whip: 1501 votes</li>
</ul>
<p>As you can see, I just ran the numbers. Feel free to double-check them. In each scenario, Clam Chowder had the same number of votes: 4500. It is clear that a vote for Creamy Cool Whip was not a vote for Clam Chowder. You know what <em>is</em> a vote for Clam Chowder? Voting for Clam Chowder.</p>
<p>The Ketchuppers are attempting to get your vote. Are you comprimising your morals if you give it to them?</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>